A Guide to the Jeremiah W. Graves Collection, 1836-1869
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Jeremiah W. Graves Collection, 1836-1869
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2012-084
0.5 cu. ft. 1 box
The Jeremiah W. Graves Collection includes a cash book, correspondence, receipts and ledger pages, newspaper clippings, and genealogy materials relating to the personal and business activities of Captain Jeremiah White Graves (1801-1878), a farmer and financial advisor/real estate broker/slave broker in Cedar Hill, Pittsylvania County, Virginia, Genealogical materials in the collection relate to the histories for branches of the Graves, Whitehead, Hunt, and Jones families.
Graves, Jeremiah White, Pittsylvania County, Va.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Jeremiah W. Graves Collection was purchased by Special Collections in October 2012.
Biographical Note
The collection relates primarily to the personal and business activities of Captain Jeremiah White Graves (1801-1878), a farmer and neighborhood financial advisor/real estate broker/slave broker who resided in Cedar Hill, Pittsylvania County, Virginia.
Scope and Content
The Jeremiah White Graves Collection includes a cash book, correspondence, receipts and ledger pages, newspaper clippings, and genealogy materials.
The manuscript portion of the collection consists of the cash book and account ledger pages documenting Graves' business ventures (sales of crops, purchases from local businesses, etc.) and correspondence created in Graves' role as real estate and slave broker, as well as letters of a personal nature exchanged between family members.
The genealogy portion of the collection includes types copies of wills, deeds, and contracts, as well as typed, compiled histories for branches of the Graves, Whitehead, and Jones and Hunt families.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically by document type.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Special Collections also holds related archival materials, the Jeremiah W. Graves Diary, Ms1990-033 (Finding Aid) and the Anna Whitehead Kenney Papers, Ms1990-022 (Finding aid), who was Jeremiah W. Graves's great-granddaughter.
Additionally, there are materials of Jeremiah W. Graves housed at the University of Virginia's Special Collections department in Charlottesville.
Index Terms
Persons:
Kenney, Anna Whitehead
Subjects:
Civil War; Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Slavery--United States; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865
Contents List
- Personal Correspondence, 1860-1883, Undated. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Business Correspondence, 1858-1879. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Individual Account Statements, 1843-1886, Undated. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Merchant Account Statements, 1872-1878. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Ephemera, 1839-1865, n.d. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Ephemera - Unidentified, n.d. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Cash Book, 1837-1853 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Wood Family Documents (Box-folder 1:8)
- Jones Family Documents, 1719-1915 (Box-folder 1:9)
- Genealogical Compilations on Graves and Whitehead Families, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 1:10)